Monsoud Zanaty III

Full Stack Software Engineer

Monsoud.Zanaty@gmail.com
monsoudzanaty.com



Software engineer with experience building consulting and personal projects within mobile development. Managed a Nonprofit organization, while leading groups of 500+ people. Brings a holistic approach to learning and development, and an Organizational Leadership focused degree.

Experience

Full Stack Engineer @ General Assembly

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021 // Washington, DC

- Build and maintain full stack MERN applications
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks, and content management systems such as JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express. Ruby.
- Plan and build projects according to the agile development cycle from concept to release, both individually in teams by implementing Git workflow

Junior Web Developer @ Birmingham Food Truck-Internship

Jan 2019 - present // Birmingham, AL

- Collaborated with a team of three, our focus was to help represent food trucks in Birmingham and allow customers the ability to find their favorites. Birmingham walkability is poor so we decided that it shouldn't be chance on how you would find the food trucks
- ▶ Develop an internal Web Front-end and Back-end in JavaScript/Node.is/React.Js.
- ▶ Interfaced with food truck owners and customers on a weekly basis to gather feedback.

Head Coach Reserves/Assistant Coach First Team @ Lane United-USL 2

April 2018 - April 2020 // Eugene, OR

- ► Analyzed game film, composed scouting reports, created opponent and internal sheets and schematics, and managed player performance before, during, and after games
- ▶ Positively lead team members while prioritizing workload and supporting organizational objectives
- Established and lead training sessions, focusing on developing Reserve Team players, and enabling their promotion to First Team when appropriate.

U9-U14 Boys and Girls Academy Director @ Colorado Rush

Aug 2018 - July 2020 // Denver, CO

- Provided coaches with comprehensive coaching education and managed recruiting, hiring, and terminating of coaches as required to maintain club standards
- Oversaw 20 teams as the Academy Director of Coaching. Managed player placement, Schedules, Training environments.
- $^{\triangleright}$ Created and implemented enhanced curricula and training methods that the club still use.

Skills

Programming & Mark-Up Languages

JavaScript (ES6), Python, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

Libraries & Frameworks

jQuery, React, Gatsby, Vue, Node.js, Express, Tailwinds, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Rails, Django

Tools & Platforms

Git, Webpack, Netlify, Heroku, Docker, MongoDB, Postman, Terminal, Discord, Slack, Zoom

Education

Valparaiso University

2010 - 2012 // Valparaiso, IN

Division 1 Soccer Player with a degree focus on Psychology.

Arizona State University

2018-2020 // Tempe, AZ

Bachelor's in organizational leadership with focus in Project Management

Projects

Jaywalkin

Web app built with React, JavaScript, and MongoDB. An E-Commerce site for sneakers using Material-UI for styling deployed with Netlify and Heroku

Odyssey

Web app built with React, JavaScript, Ruby, and MongoDB. A Blogsite using Material-UI for styling. Deployed with Netlify and Heroku

Interests

Soccer, Snowboarding, Cycling, Camping, Traveling, Reading, Hiking